resavenue.com 2019-03-05

# ResAvenue :: Online Hotel Reservation Software With Global Distribution System (GDS) and Internet Distribution System (IDS) Connectivity :: Privacy Policy

**ResAvenue** a brand operating under **Infibeam Avenues Limited** (we/us/our) take privacy and data protection issues seriously. We have designed this Privacy Policy to explain how we handle personally identifiable information collected from Customers/Users (you/ your) who use services of ResAvenue directly or through any third party, submit information to ResAvenue through the Internet. As ResAvenue services evolve, we may revise this policy, so please check back frequently. If you have questions about ResAvenue privacy practices, please contact us at [ infosec@avenues.info.](mailto:infosec@avenues.info.)

ResAvenue being a responsible organisation acknowledge the importance of right to privacy. Customers all across the globe place their trust on us by transacting though ResAvenue and we at ResAvenue value that trust. And we are committed to protect and safeguard your personal data. 

This Policy also covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that ResAvenue back end technology providers/partners designated solution provider or distribution partner may share with it. This document describes the usage of your personal data acquired by ResAvenue. 

This Policy sets out how we will use and protect your information. We will use your personal information only for the purposes and in the manner allowed by the applicable data protection laws. We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy carefully. 

**1\. Kind of Personal Data Collected by ResAvenue:**

ResAvenue asks Customers to supply various personal data when placing an online order, such as name and address, telephone number, and E-mail address. We collect Customer’s name, contact details, and Customer’s Debit/Credit Card Details and other details as per several payment options. (we collect the Debit/Credit Card details and other payment details, as per the rules and regulation law, established by the Reserve Bank of India and Card Companies). In addition to curb down the chance of risk and fraud we also collect information from Customer’s computer, phone, tablet or other device Customers are using to access our services. This includes the IP address, the browser, and Customer’s language settings. There are also situations in which we receive information about Customer from others or automatically collect other information. This is the basic overview of the information we collect. 

We may also receive information about you from other sources. These include business partners, such as affiliate partners designated solution provider or distribution partner, and other independent third parties, and anything we get from them may be combined with information provided by you. 

**2\. Reason for Collecting and Processing the Data :**

We collect the personal information to render our services efficiently. To curb down the chance and risk of online/ offline frauds. In process to provide our service we, are required to have the personal information of the Customer to authorise and complete the transactions or requests of the Customers. We process and collect your information mainly for the following purposes: 

  * To help you purchase/ acquire the Products/Services/Reservations that you have requested and to process any payment connected with that Products/Services Reservations as requested. 
  * To contact you if required in relation to the Product/Services/Reservations that you have purchased/requested to any communications that you might have sent us. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and our partner hotels or between us and the hotel partner you are making your booking on or the hotel partners’ designated solution provider or distribution partner. 
  * To provide you with customer care 
  * For security and fraud prevention purposes 
  * To help improve our Applications and our Services 
  * The use of this information is necessary for the purpose of our legitimate interests. 

We will also process personal data as is necessary to comply with any of our legal obligations. We will inform you in advance if we intend to further process your personal data for a purpose other than as set out above. We will also seek your specific consent to the processing of personal data for other specific purposes. You will have the right to withdraw such consent at any time. 

**3\. Sharing of Data**

We currently share your personal data, where necessary, with the following recipients: 

  * you and, where you request, any third party you ask us to share it with; 
  * Our partnering Banks, ResAvenue Merchants, Hoteliers and Facility providers and their designated solution providers or distribution partners. 
  * governmental, legal, regulatory, or similar authorities, on request or where required, including for the purposes of reporting any actual or suspected breach of applicable law or regulation; 
  * direct marketing service providers; 
  * data analytics service providers, 
  * third party service providers used for the delivery of some aspects of the Services (e.g. SMS delivery, email delivery, web notifications, app notifications and phone number lookup); 

Our Applications may, interface with third party services that you have previously interacted with (e.g. Facebook), or contain links to third party content. Please note that ResAvenue is not responsible for such services or content, or the privacy policies associated with those services or content. We recommend that you review any third party’s privacy policy before accessing such services or content. 

**4\. Security of Your Personal Data**

As stated above we are heavily regulated body and our operation are monitored by the Reserve Bank of India, Our Partnering Banks and Card Companies. We abide by the provisions of Indian Information Technology Act 2000 and its Rules and all relevant amendments, we also have the certification of PCIDSS (a set of rules and regulation by the Card Companies), Infibeam Avenues Limited is ISO27001 compliant and all brands under the aegis of the company are compliant too. ResAvenue protects, processes and uses all the data collected in accordance with the applicable Data Protection Laws. 

ResAvenue observe reasonable procedures to prevent unauthorized access to, and the misuse of, personal data collected by ResAvenue.

We use appropriate business systems and procedures to protect and safeguard the personal data you give us. We also use security procedures and technical and physical restrictions for accessing and using the personal data on our servers. Only authorized personnel are permitted to access personal data in the course of their work.

We will retain your personal data for as long as we deem it necessary to enable you to use our services, to provide our services to you (including maintaining the online user account (if created)), to comply with applicable laws, resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business, including to detect and prevent fraud or other illegal activities. All personal data we retain will be subject to this Privacy Policy. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal data we process about you, please contact us via the contact details provided below. 

**5\. Control of Data**

Customer has all the right and control over their personal data provided to us. Customer can request us for an overview of their data by putting up a mail to us. In certain situations, you can ask us to modify, erase, or block or restrict the processing of, the personal data we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal data; and 

We rely on you to ensure that your personal data is complete, accurate and current. Please do inform us promptly of any changes to or inaccuracies of to your personal data by contacting us. 

ResAvenue want Customers to be in control of how personal data is used by us. Customer can do this in the following ways: 

  * You a can ask us for a copy of the personal data we hold about that particular individual; 
  * You can inform us of any changes to their personal data, or can ask us to correct any of the personal data we hold about them 
  * An individual can ask us to erase, or block or restrict the processing of, the personal data we hold about them, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal data; and 
  * In certain situations, individual can also ask us to send the personal data; we have given to a third party. 

Where we are using personal data on the basis of individual’s consent, He/she is entitled to withdraw that consent at any time subject to applicable law. Moreover, where we process personal data based on legitimate interest or the public interest, individual have the right to object at any time to that use of personal data subject to applicable law. 

If you wish to object to the processing of your personal data on the basis of legitimate interest and no opt-out mechanism is available, please contact us at [infosec@avenues.info](mailto:infosec@avenues.info).

**6\. Personal Data of Children**

ResAvenue services are only allowed to be use by people over 16 years of age. We only process information about children with the consent of the parents or legal guardians or when the information is provided to us by the parents or legal guardian.

**7\. Personal Data Received from Other Sources.**

We may also receive information about you from other sources. These include business partners, such as affiliate partners designated solution provider or distribution partner, and other independent third parties, and anything we get from them may be combined with information provided by you. 

**8\. What if ResAvenue is bought by Another Company?**

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your personal data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company. The third party must only use your personal data for the purposes that you provided it to us in the first place and as set out in this privacy notice. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer. 

**9\. Cookies**

**  What is a Cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file of letters and numbers that is stored by the browser on your computer when you visit certain websites. A cookie allows a website to distinguish your computer from other users’ computers.  Cookies do not contain Personal Data unless you have already given this information to the Website. You may delete or block the cookies, if that is what you choose to do. Note that this may make it less convenient for you to use our websites.

If you would like to view the information that we have collected from you or you want to correct your information or the billing/shipping details, you can mail us at [infosec@avenues.info](mailto:infosec@avenues.info) or write to us at: 

**Infibeam Avenues Limited.,  
Plaza Asiad, Level Two   
Station Road, Santa Cruz (West),   
Mumbai 400 054. India.**

We respond to subpoenas, warrants, or other court orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs concerning any Merchant, customer or visitor. We reserve the right to release that information concerning any -Merchant/customer who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities.  
We also reserve the right to report any illegal activity by any Customers to law enforcement for prosecution.

Please be aware that ResAvenue does not warrant the acts of its Merchants or Customers or visitors. All Customers and visitors should be aware that, when they disclose personal information such as their actual name, stores’ name, e-mail address, etc. to third parties, the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside of ResAvenue. In the event that you encounter any ResAvenue Merchant who is improperly collecting or using information about users or Customers, please contact us by emailing at [infosec@avenues.info](mailto:infosec@avenues.info)
